Esta lição 24 de Pimsleur Inglês 1.
Listen to this conversation. Is gas expensive
in America? No, it's not very expensive. How much is it?
$1 or $2 per gallon. Do you have a car?
Yes, I do. Listen again. Is gas
expensive in America? No, it's not very expensive.
How much is it? One or two dollars per gallon. Do you have a car?
Yes, I do. Tell me that you're Brazilian.
Diga-me que você é brasileiro. Tell me that you're Brazilian.
I'm Brazilian.
Tell me. Diga-me. Tell me that you live in Rio.
I live in Rio.
Tell me that you are going to America.
I'm going to America.
Tell me that you have a car.
I have a car.
Tell me that you have a small car.
I have a small car.
Tell me that you'd like a bigger car.
I'd like a bigger car.
A bigger car. Tell me
that you are going to America with your family.
I'm going to America with my family.
Ask how many people there are in my family.
How many people are there in your family?
Say, há três pessoas na nossa família.
There are
three people in our family.
Nós temos uma família pequena.
We have a small family.
Say, nós temos uma família maior.
We have a bigger family.
A bigger family.
Há cinco pessoas na nossa família.
There are five people in our family.
Mas nós queremos um carro menor.
But we want a smaller car.
A smaller car.
Ask if gas is expensive in America. Ask if
gas is expensive in America.
Is gas expensive in America?
Listen. No, gas isn't very expensive
in America. Ask how much it is.
How much is it?
Usando o número, diga um dólar por galão.
One dollar per gallon.
Ask me how much gas I want.
How much gas do you want?
Say, enche o tanque, por favor.
Fill it up, please.
Say, isso é demais.
That's too
much. That's too much.
Aqui é mais caro.
Here it's more expensive.
More expensive.
Aqui a gasolina custa dois dólares por galão.
Here, gas is two dollars per gallon.
Now ask: Long Island fica longe?
Is Long Island far?
Você quer perguntar fica a que distância ou literalmente
quão longe fica. Listen and repeat. How far
is it?
How far?
Far. How far is it?
Pergunte-me outra vez, quão longe fica?
How far is it?
How far is it to Long Island?
Sei, não muito longe.
Not very far.
It's not very far.
Say, a estrada para Long Island.
The road to Long Island.
The road. Ask, é esta
a estrada para Long Island?
Is this the road to Long Island?
Say, no, a estrada para Long Island.
No, the road to Long Island.
Fica adiante.
Is straight ahead.
The road to Long Island is straight ahead.
Quão longe fica?
How far is it?
How many
miles? Try to say 74
74 miles.
It's 74 miles.
How do you say Eu quero gasolina.
I want some gas.
Some gas.
Eu preciso de gasolina. Listen and repeat.
I need some gas.
Need. Need.
I need. I need
some gas.
Say again. Eu preciso de gasolina.
I need some gas.
How do you say? Você precisa.
You need. Now try to ask.
Você precisa de gasolina?
Do you need some gas?
Como ele responde brevemente que sim.
Yes, I do.
Yes, I need some gas.
Say, Enche o tanque, por favor.
Fill it up, please.
Say, Isso é suficiente.
That's enough.
That's enough gas.
Now say, nós temos um carro pequeno.
We have a small car.
Try to say, nós precisamos de um carro maior.
We need a bigger car.
Ask. Você tem uma família grande?
Do you have a big family?
Usando nós, tente responder brevemente que sim.
Yes, we do.
Quantas pessoas há na sua família?
How many people are there in your family?
Há seis pessoas na nossa família.
There are six people in our family.
Nós temos uma família menor.
We have a smaller family.
E nós queremos um carro menor.
And we want a smaller car.
Say, desculpe-me.
Excuse me.
Ci scusimi, è questa strada per Long Island?
Excuse me, is this the road to Long Island?
Não, fica à direita. Listen and repeat.
No, it's to the right.
Right. Right.
The right.
To. To the right.
It's to the right. Say again. Fica à direita.
It's to the right.
Vá para a direita. Listen and repeat.
Go to the right.
Go. Go.
Go to the right. Sai, vá para a direita.
Go to the right.
Você se lembra de como se diz você quer?
You want. Try to say a
estrada que você quer, literalmente a estrada você
quer.
The road you want.
You want. The road
you want. A estrada
que você quer fica à direita.
The road you want is to the right.
Ask à direita,
to the right,
ou adiante, or straight
ahead. Or straight ahead.
Siga adiante. Em inglês, vá e siga são o mesmo.
Go straight ahead.
Ask verdade.
Really? Espere.
Wait. Wait. A estrada que você quer fica à esquerda.
Listen and repeat. The road you want is
to the left.
Left. Left.
To the left.
Say, à esquerda.
To the left. A estrada
que você quer fica à esquerda.
The road you want is to the left.
Try to say, a estrada que eu quero.
The road I want.
The road
I want.
Now try to ask. A estrada que eu quero fica à
Is the road I want to the left?
Answer: No, fica adiante.
No, it's straight ahead.
Say: Não.
No, it's not to the left.
It's not to the left.
Now say, vá para a direita.
Go to the right.
Essa é a estrada
que você quer. That's the road
That's the road you want.
Say, vá para a direita.
Go to the right.
Vá para a esquerda.
Go to the left.
E depois adiante. Listen and repeat.
And then straight ahead.
Then. Then.
Você já usou? Then, com significado de então,
pode também significar depois. Tiga outra vez
e depois adiante.
And then straight ahead.
Essa é a estrada para Long Island.
That's the road to Long Island.
Quan longi fica?
How far is it?
São setenta milhas.
It's seventy miles.
Seventy. It's seventy miles.
Say that you need some gas. Say that you need
some gas. I need
some gas. Peça ao empregado
do posto para encher o tanque.
Fill it up. Fill it up,
please.
Pergunte quanto custa.
How much is it?
Referindo-se ao número, diga um dólar por galão.
One dollar per gallon.
São dez dólares. Diga literalmente: isso é
dez dólares.
That's ten dollars.
One dollar per gallon. That's ten dollars.
O que você diz ao lhe dar dez dólares?
Here. Here's ten dollars.
Ask if this is the road to Long Island.
Is this the road to Long Island?
Escute sua resposta. No, it isn't.
No, it isn't. Say: A estrada que você quer.
The road you want.
A estrada que você quer fica à direita.
The road you want is to the right.
Vá para
a direita. Go to
the right. Depois,
para a esquerda.
Then, to the left.
How do you say? Espere, eu não entendo.
Wait, I don't understand.
Você fala rápido demais.
You speak too fast.
Por favor, repita.
Please repeat.
Onde fica a estrada para Long Island?
Where is the road to Long Island?
Esta é a estrada para Long Island?
Is this the road to Long Island?
Não, a estrada que você quer.
No, the road you want.
A estrada que você quer fica lá.
The road you want is over there.
Vá para a direita.
Go to the right.
Depois, vá para a esquerda.
Then go to the left.
E depois siga setenta milhas adiante.
And then go seventy miles straight ahead.
Long Island não fica muito longe.
Long Island isn't very far.
Quantas milhas são?
How many miles is it?
São setenta e cinco milhas.
It's seventy-five miles.
Eu preciso de gasolina.
I need some gas.
Some gas.
Now ask: A
gasolina cara?
Is gas expensive?
Usando o número, diga: Não, custa um dólar por
No, it's one dollar per gallon.
E você tem um carro pequeno.
And you have a small car.
Então enche o tanque, por favor.
Then fill it up, please.
Mas a estrada para Long Island fica.
But is the road to Long Island à
esquerda ou à direita?
To the left or to the right?
Ou adiante. Or straight
ahead.
Or straight ahead.
Answer: Eu não sei.
I don't know. And now say:
Até logo, senhor.
Goodbye,
sir. Goodbye,
sir. Nesta lição
de inglês 1 se incluem exercícios de leitura.